why don't I use Linux on the desktop um
I got this question yet again today and
so I'm going to make a video on it I've
made tons of videos about it before I
get asked this question all the time so
I'm going to answer it one more time and
we're going to make a video and I'm
going to put the video in uh the Linux
section uh the Linux stage of the
beginner boost so you can understand why
this this answer has very direct
relevance to everyone watching who wants
a job in technology okay the answer is
Linux on the desktop is not the best
tool for the job and um I probably need
to make another video about what it even
means to say the best tool for the job
right but it goes without saying right
and I am a live streamer who has my bike
right here this is my indoor bike right
here and that is the short answer the
short answer as to why I don't use Linux
on the desktop is because it
sucks it's totally horrible it's the
disaster and that will be the tagline
Linux on the desktop
sucks it really does it has and this is
from a guy who's used Linux on the
desktop for 25 years I have been I use
Linux on the desktop my entire career at
IBM I use Linux on the desktop my entire
career as a teleporter for building an
internet service provider I know what
I'm talking about I have used every
Linux desktop that
exists and so when I say that it sucks
I'm telling you it sucks you cannot use
Linux for solid works you cannot use
Linux for anything with 3ds Max you
cannot use Linux for major Enterprise
applications that are demanded and
required you
can't you just can't use it I spent and
there are videos of this I spent more
than a day total in hours and I did it
all live because I was like I'm going to
try Vulcan I'm going to try bottles I'm
going to try this and this and this and
I could not get my absolute favorite
most important game to work zift zift is
the game that I live by and you know
people say it's a skill issue I say
please refer to the 24 or to the 12
hours of video I made trying to get zift
to work on Linux and Mr 10x troll
programmer who loves to talk [__] like
this all the time is a good example of
the type of [__] I've had to deal with
because I'm using the right tool for the
job I know Linux because I the fact that
I can't get Linux to work on the desktop
has nothing to do with me and by the way
this is the same problem that lennis
does Tech had when that huge drama
happened last year he tried to just do
something extremely simple and all the
Linux Community came on glued saying oh
you're doing it wrong you're doing this
wrong this wrong he like I don't know I
just want to install my game and have it
work you know how long it takes me to
install and get zift to work you know
how long it takes me to install and get
Linux to work for my zift game less than
10 minutes I just install it I download
this the thing I put it on and plug I
plug it I plug in my my I plug in my
bike I get on my bike and I start to do
it yeah here comes 10x again 10x is
going to have fun with me on this one
this this this is what happens every
time you say something bad about Linux
if you say anything bad about anything
about Linux you get you get the arch
people that come out of the thing and
they love to have fun with you you know
what most of them don't have jobs doing
Linux I'm saying they don't and if they
have had a jobs doing Linux they haven't
been doing it for a long time and if you
tell them that you can't run solid works
the most important piece of software
many would argue for doing any kind of
like Computer
Engineering they're like oh they'd
pretend it doesn't exist and they look
the other way and like oh well yeah yeah
if you want to do that but why would you
want to do that so if you're going to
fight with me about by the way most of
the people who use desktop Linux have no
idea how to use t-o they've never done
it they don't know why to use it they're
like why are you doing that why don't
you just use neovim pains they don't
even understand the implications of
these things because they're usually
noobs the people who are pushing for
Linux on the desktop are usually noobs
and the ones that that hit people over
the head I saw this is a true story I
saw a seasoned veteran het Tannis who
who has several certifications in Linux
has taught at the University level for
several years and has set up Linux
systems and servers for corporations and
and and Noah and a bunch of huge
organizations and I sat there and
watched people in his twitch chat saying
and one guy and I quote exactly one
person said does any anyone else think
this guy is sus for not running Linux on
his
desktop while he was configuring his
multi-cluster Linux cluster VM using the
tool of his preference on a Windows
system while he was streaming this
random Noob was giving him crap in the
chat because he didn't run Linux on the
desktop and I was like holy cow I was
like what the hell is wrong with these
people and if that's you I'm so sorry
I'm so sorry that that's you I don't
mean to so when people say where's your
Linux and they like pull their arms at
me and they they don't even know that I
streamed from Linux for two and a half
years for two and a half years I
streamed from Linux way before the other
twitch streamers were streaming from
Linux by the way a lot of them are doing
that now and they finally caught up it's
so funny because there's a number of
streamers right now that are streaming
from Linux on the desktop and they're
using things like screen key and and and
I actually wrote a custom Clips
integration I loved having Linux on the
desktop for streaming
but as soon as I couldn't do my games
primarily zift and I couldn't use
probably 60% of the plugins that are
available for OBS which is a streaming
platform thing as soon as that became
the truth then Linux on the desktop
stopped being the best tool for the job
now there again there are some serious
things that I would I really miss I miss
being able to run clips from the
terminal and have it just open I miss
being able to do text based browsing
using links and and hit the period and
have it open up my graphic browser
because there's a job script dependency
there are a lot of really solid reasons
to do that but those are trumped for me
by the fact that other higher priority
tools just don't work in the Linux
desktop and this is not a skills issue
this is it doesn't work and if you can
prove to me that zift works inside of a
Linux desktop you leave the comments in
the section but I want to see a video of
you doing it because so far nobody's
done it and the people who finally do
get it to work guess what they end up
having to do zift reases a platform
update and what happens the entire thing
shits the bed because it won't work and
I have to go in there and hand customize
my thing you know else I can just do run
Windows on the desktop so and and by the
way Rob Pike one of the most influential
he pretty much invented Unicode not to
mention he's put satellites in the air
he was part of the Unix original thing
he hung out with he hung out with with
the creators of Unix and C Dennis
Richards was his personal friend he was
the primary contributor and developer of
the go programming language which is the
number one language in Enterprise right
now uses a Mac and if you don't like
that because he's using a Mac and if
you're going to say he's lesser of a
programmer because he's not running a
Linux laptop with Linux on the desktop
that problem is on you not him Mike drop